# **HECTOR ANTONIO SANCHEZ JOHNSON**

Charlotte, NC | 980-242-9742 | hector.sanchez.johnson@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/hector-sanchez

## FINTECH SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

IT professional with 10+ years of experience in a variety of roles, such as Senior Developer, Project Manager and ITSM Team Lead. Exemplary record in revenue generation through top-tier IT development and project administration. With a passion for Machine Learning and Data Science in FinTech and starting in Blockchain development, as well as algorithmic trading strategies for the financial markets. Self-motivated, adaptable, quick-learning and award-winning, with proven global experience helping companies to achieve their revenue-generation goals within scope, quality, time, and cost constraints. Multi-lingual (English, Spanish, Japanese, German, French).

### **SKILLS**

Organization | Communication | Leadership | Team Spirit | Solidarity | Creativity | Initiative | Collaboration |
Persuasion | Adaptability | Emotional Intelligence | Social Intelligence | Versatility | Flexibility | Analytical
Reasoning | UX Design | Frontend Developer | Project Management | Kaizen | ITIL | Agile | SAFe | Six Sigma |
React | Angular | JavaScript | Python | HTML | CSS | .NET/C# | Blockchain | Volunteering

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**LPL Financial |** Fort Mill, NC, US

# Sr. Developer for Digital Marketing

August 2019 - February 2022

Seasoned in React, Angular, JavaScript, CSS UI/UX design and development, specializing in the company site and intranet portal, along with advanced SharePoint administration. Facilitated companywide intranet portal as well as all Team Sites used throughout the company for teams to itemize and track daily activities.

- Created from scratch a new Request process and managed to delegate 100% of non-development activities to 2nd level TOPS support. Thanks to this effort we were able avoid over 400 monthly emails and speed up request delivery by 300%.
- Facilitated the automation of the most voluminous requests by coordinating multiple teams, achieving an automated implementation rate of 75% of requests.
- Developed from scratch a new onboarding application in Angular to grow business by 15%.
- Secured a confirmed data breach of Personal Information by developing protection against bot attacks, securing 100% of scoped data at risk.

Syntax (ex Freudenberg IT) | Puebla, Mexico

**February 2019 – August 2019** 

# **Steering Project Coordinator**

Manage, track, report and forecast all internal and external customer projects including environment design, server and application builds, decommissions, network implementations, among others.

- Self-taught ServiceNow backend development to create a decommission metrics dashboard that expedited delivery by 60% and decreased overdue decommissions by almost 30% in under 2 months; Recovering physical Data Center capacity and saving unused expenditure.
- Pioneered a server build metrics dashboard that streamlined task handover and increased team awareness, increasing build delivery by 25%.

T-Systems Mexico | Puebla, Mexico

August 2012 – February 2019

T-Systems Mexico | Lead Incident Manager, Problem Manager, Change Manager January 2018 – February 2019 Handle command center calls for all customers and manage all high and critical major incidents on demand along with T-Systems Global (Germany). Coordinate efforts between managers and teams to identify and remediate the root causes behind all service issues and maintain service level agreement KPIs through targeted reporting and follow-up meetings.

• Became the first T-Systems employee ever to hold 3 Process Quality Management positions at the same time: Incident, Change, and Problem Management.

- Saved T-Systems 50% in resource expenditure for quality processes, and increased productivity 33% by creating weekly schedule to integrate the incident, change, and problem management; developed processspecific days instead of process-specific roles/resources.
- Decreased weekly change errors by 70% and increased monthly KPI for successful changes to 99% in less than 1 year. Initially, change management team went through a staff downsizing and therefore struggled to review the daily volume of 100+ weekly change tickets to maintain monthly KPI of 95% successful changes; established specific change review strategy.
- Improved timely problem ticket closure by 66% in less than 1 year, increasing the overall KPI to 95% of total
  volume; initially, problem management team was understaffed for the 300+ problem ticket volume per year
  required to maintain yearly KPI of 90% tickets closed within deadline; joined team and redistributed account
  management per team resources; set up deep-dive reviews.

**T-Systems Mexico | Lead Incident Manager, Incident Management Team Manager,** July 2016 – December 2017 Maintained, developed, and improved incident management processes, tools, and documentation. Managed eight employees.

- Saved almost \$130K per year after discovering company-wide notification tool that was 75% less expensive than the one inherited.
- Reduced response time to trigger alarm chain consistently by 25%.

**T-Systems Mexico | MW Team Lead for COPART, ConnectedCar and Daimler VB,** May 2014 – July 2016 Managed team resources, schedules, on-call, customer satisfaction, escalations, and financials. Kept track of financials for 1000+ solution delivery elements (SDEs) for multiple customers, which included all technical specifications per item, and delivered monthly reports on inventory, startups (new items) and rundowns (decommissions). Managed 10 employees.

- Awarded the highest company award— "Silver Run for Best Project of the Year: Daimler Vehicle Backend for 96.5% Effectiveness"; Daimler Vehicle Backend was an important account because implementation would bring in more business from the customer; went to Frankfurt, DE, for 2 weeks to manage service transition.
- Won first place in a competition called "T-Race: Process Improvement for Customer Satisfaction" by creating 30+ pre-populated change models in two months; calculated the metrics of standard requests within the MW team for all customers; worked together with the change management team to create as many models as possible to enhance productivity/ speed up the delivery of standard requests.

## T-Systems Mexico | MW Senior Support Specialist,

October 2012 – May 2014

Oversaw technical activities involving WSO2, Apache, Tomcat, LifeRay, and MySQL. Handled an average monthly volume of 150+ service requests, 30+ changes, and 7+ high-priority incidents/problems while serving COPART, OneAmerica, Volkswagen Mexico, and Grupo Modelo.

- Awarded highest company award— "Silver Sun for Best Project of the Year: COPART for 99% Effectiveness";
   COPART was a sensitive account due to many development projects and MW support; spent countless night shifts performing change requests to keep systems functioning optimally, as well as fixing high-priority downtimes to restore service as soon as possible.
- Traveled to Las Vegas, NV, for yearly RoleSwap of primary to secondary servers.

# T-Systems Mexico | BusinessObjects Junior Support Specialist,

August 2012 – October 2012

Performed technical activities for BusinessObjects Enterprise, Crystal Reports, InfoBurst, MSSQL.

- Worked with a team of three business objects specialists for the biggest client at the time, McKesson.
- Participated in a month-long BusinessObjects and Crystal Reports Academy.

# **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

Master of Business Administration (Minor: Project Management), Universidad de las Américas Puebla, Mexico Bachelor's Degree in Electronics Engineering and Telecommunications, UDLAP, Puebla, Mexico Studied Abroad at 関西外国語大学 — Kansai Gaikokugo Daigaku, Osaka, Japan

## Dennett-Pinker Innovation for Humanity Scholarship Essay Contest Winner for City of Ideas, Puebla, Mexico

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Agile/SAFe Foundations | 6σ YB | WorkFusion Automation Kit for Enterprise, Automating the Business Process | ITIL Certifications: Foundations, Service Operation, Service Strategy, Continual Service Improvement, Service Transition | Lean IT Foundations | Entrepreneur Youth Talent of Puebla | Finance for Non-Finance Majors | High-Performance Team Development | WSO2 Carbon Administrator | Maximum Financial Transformation | Business Model and Strategy, Marketing and Accounting | Conflict Resolution

### **HONORS**

Hand-picked to give a technical presentation and host a technology-focused workshop: (1) International Symposium of Business and Accounts, Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla presentation on "The Era of Apps" in front of 3500+ guests (2018); and (2) Second Women Geeks Forum by Geeks MX workshop on "How to Buy and Sell Online." |

Finalist – "Puebla App Innovation '18" by Geeks MX: Presenting the OPS Sustainable Online Marketplace. | Finalist – "Sustainable Innovation '18" by Socialab: Presenting the OPS Sustainable Online Marketplace.

### **ENTREPRENEURSHIP**

Founded two technical service organizations: (1) Ten Sai Digital Solutions, a provider of freelance Web and mobile software development; and (2) the Organic People Society (OPS), a sustainable online marketplace.

## COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Chair of the Hispanic Organization of Latin Accomplishment (HOLA) ERG – LPL Financial, Fort Mill, SC Internal community with an outreach program to create lasting relations with external organizations.

Executive Board Member & Chief Technology Officer – Jalo Puebla (NGO), Puebla, MX

Logistics and deliveries of relief supplies after the 2017 earthquake in Morelos, MX, and other natural disasters.

Chief Technology Officer – Epicentro Puebla (NGO), Puebla, MX

Developed a web portal for users to map affected areas and register required supplies.